Prabhat Kumar

Mobile: +91-7827320278 | Email: kmrprabhat@outlook.com



Software developer with 11+ years of experience and broad knowledge of engineering and software technology. In-depth knowledge of design, development, and sustenance of product systems and subsystems. Strictly adhered to time schedules and successfully accomplished engineering and organizational mission. Currently working as a Computer Scientist at Adobe Systems Inc.

CAPABILITIES & SKILLS

- As a computer scientist, delivered highly complex technical work products.
- Developed multiple mobile and web apps for several NGOs as a volunteer.
- Designed and developed web app for environment and sustainability.
- Submitted internal white paper on standardization for linguistic testing and developed a tool which has been adopted as de facto tool for linguistic testing.
- Ability to troubleshoot issues to resolution. Strong problem solving and root cause analysis skills.
- Strong oral & written communication skills including facilitating, listening, and presentation.

Technical Skills – JAVA, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks – Angular 4+, React JS

Business Domain – Localization, Advertisements, Energy, logistics & e-commerce

Languages – English & Hindi.

EDUCATION

| Bachelor of Engineering | 2010 |
|--|------|
| Electronics and communication. Birla Institute of Technology Mesra | |
| Sr Secondary School | 2005 |
| Science Math's. Shri Mahaveer Digambar Jain c-scheme Jaipur | |
| Secondary School | 2003 |
| Science. Shivaji Inter College Kanpur | |

TRAININGS

ESI Certified Business Analyst. Certified agile training.

Pro Bono work and awards/recognition

Maharashtra Govt – Green building initiative, where we help assess the building rating of the existing building (15K+). With our help we saved around 10Cr+ to Govt and reduced the timeline from 12 months to 1month. Received Certificate from Honorable Minister of Road Transport and Highways (MoRTH) Sh. Nitin Jairam Gadkari, who were personally involved and praised the efforts.

Griha – Helped design a platform to assess building readiness while opening office after covid, and help the organization prepare better. All the Govt Organization are using that platform including ISRO, PWD, Indian Army and Indian Airforce and Ministries. Received written recognition from DR. Ajay Mathur (Director general International Solar Alliance & CEO Griha)

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE



Adobe Systems India Inc | Computer Scientist | Internationalization and localization

October 2017 to present

Internationalization is the process of designing a software application so that it can be adapted to various languages and regions without engineering changes. Localization is the process of adapting internationalized software for a specific region or language by adding locale-specific components and translating text.

- Developed new Adobe localization Framework toolkit to translate all Adobe Products
- Developed automatic linguistic bug creation and fix for linguistic error and generated reporting dashboard, which improved bug fixing significantly.
- Developed system for automated translation of help documents using markdown

Times Internet Ltd (Times of India Group) | Manager level II | Colombia

June 2016 to October 2017

Colombia is a smart marketing platform that allows marketers to connect with digital consumers and processing billions of requests a day and matching the right marketing offer to the right users at the right time and the right format, considers more than 1,000 separate attributes in real time. It engages with nearly 200 million digital users a month across Times Internet Ltd properties and partner publisher

- Developed self-service portal for ad serving platform.
- Create multiple types of ad methods to optimize and enhance ad consumption.
- Created additional parameters to efficient targeting.

SSN Logistics Pvt Ltd (Delhivery) | Senior Associate Technology | LMAP

November 2015 to June 2016

LMAP is decoupling last module as a separate Product, which enables performance enhancement, Mobile approach and reducing risk.

- Developed webapp for LMAP(Last Mile As Product).
- Rolled out to 500+ centers and supported roll out operations.
- Handled half a million packages data and reliably integrated with third party service providers.

Wipro Technologies Ltd | Sr. Software Engineer

April 2011 to November 2015

InSite is a Data management services can be a key enabler, allowing drilling and other relevant rig site data to be collected, transmitted, replicated, and managed in real time. The InSite service is a common platform for replicating well site data generated and acquired by Sperry. I have also managed end to end automation testing

- Developed NexGen Insite platform
- Developed first prototype of Insite Anywhere web Product
- Managed end to end automation testing using Jenkins.